지난 이야기..
Previously on Hannibal...
캐시 보일은 홉스가 죽이지 않았어요
Gareth Jacob Hobbs didn't kill
Cassie Boyle.
- 알아요
- 아빠, 아빠 전화예요
- I know.
- Dad, it's for you.
전 그 전화를 건 사람이
모방범죄자라고 확신합니다
I believe the as yet unidentified caller
was our copycat killer.
집에 가고 싶어요
I wanna go home.
자주 해요?
You do this a lot?
현장에 가서 살인을 상상하는 거요
Go places and think about killing.
아주 자주
Too often.
난 죽이지 않았어
I didn't kill that girl.
배를 가른 건 정당방위가 성립 안 돼
This is in self defense Abigail.
You butchered him.
전화 했던 거 알아요
You're the one who called the house.
네 비밀은 지켜줄게
I'll keep your secret.
박사님 비밀도요
And I'll keep yours.
가끔...
Sometimes...
어두운 밤에
집에 불을 켜놓은 채로
at night I leave the lights on
in my little house.
들판으로 걸어나가요
And... walk across the flat fields
멀리서 집을 바라보면
바다에 떠있는 한 척의 배 같죠
When I look back from a distance,
the house is like a boat on the sea.
안전하다고 느끼는 건 그때뿐이에요
It's really the only time I feel safe.
홉스의 집에 섰을 때
적막을 느꼈다고 했죠?
You stood in the breathing silence of
Gareth Jacob Hobbs' home,
그의 공간에 섰을 때요
the very spaces he moved through.
말해봐요...
적막 속에서 뭐가 들렸죠?
Tell me Will... Did they speak to you?
소음과 그의 목소리요
With noise and clarity.
마치 본능처럼..
그의 광기를 느꼈나요?
You could sense his madness,
like a bloodhound...
홉스에가 다가가려고
온 힘을 다했어요
I tried so hard to know
Gareth Jacob Hobbs.
그를 알기 위해서요
To see him.
가렛 제이콥 홉스! FBI다!
Gareth Jacob Hobbs, FBI!
슬라이드, 증거물, 보고서
그 너머를 보기 위해서
Past the slides and viles,
beyond the lines of the police report,
슬픔이 선명하게 박힌
between the pixels of all those
희생자들이 사진 너머를 보기 위해서요
printed faces of sad dead girls.
이제 알겠어?
See.
멜리사를 발견했을 때
어떤 기분이 들었죠?
How did you feel seeing Marissa Shore,
impaled in his antler room?
죄책감
Guilty.
구하지 못해서요?
Because you couldn't save her.
내가 죽인 것처럼 느껴져서요..
Because I felt like I killed her...
홉스에게 아주 가까이 다가갔어요
I got so close to him.
가끔은...
Sometimes...
마치 홉스처럼 행동하는 것 같아죠
I felt like we were doing the same things
at different times of day
그와 같은 시간에
먹고 씻고 자는 것처럼요
like I was eating
or showering or sleeping
at the same time he was.
죽은 후에도요?
Even after he was dead?
네, 죽은 후에도요
Even after he was dead.
마치...
Like...
그가 되어가는 것처럼요?
you were becoming him.
난 내가 누군지 알아요
I know who I am.
난 홉스가 아니에요, 박사
I'm not Gareth Jacob Hobbs,
Doctor Lecter.
식탁이 차려져 있다
Table has been set.
가족 만찬
Family dinner.
난 초대받지 않았다
I wasn't invited.
난 식탁 앞쪽에 자릴 잡고 앉는다
I take my seat at the head of the table.
내가 택한 자리는
터너 부인의 옆자리
My seat.
My place setting next to Mrs. Turner.
내가 주빈이다
I am the guest of honor.
아무도 음식에 손을 대지 않았다
Nobody has taken a bite of their dinner.
채소를 안 먹으면 디저트는 없어
If you don't eat your growing foods,
you won't get any dessert.
아무도 식탁을 떠나지 마!
No one leaves the table.
모두 두려움에 얼어붙는다
All afraid to move,
아이들까지도 꼼짝하지 않는다
even the little ones behave themselves.
이 만찬에 내 가족들을 데려와서
I brought my own family
to this home invasion.
거친 위협으로 터너 일가를 통제한다
Controlling the Turners
with threats of violence
그리고 위협은 실행으로 옮겨진다
threats that turn to action.
터너 부인을 제외한
가족들은 동시에 처형된다
The Turner family
is executed simultaneously.
With the exception of Mrs. Turner
부인이 마지막이다
who dies last.
이건 나의 그림이다
This is my design.
내가 터너 부인을 쏜다
I shoot Mrs. Turner.
뭐가 보여요?
What do you see Will?
가족의 가치요
Family values.
어느 가족의 가치요?
Who's family values?
희생자는 카렌, 로저 터너
그리고 어린 두 딸
Alright, Karen and Roger Turner,
childhood sweethearts.
부동산업으로 성공한 자산가에
Owned a successful realestate business.
지역적 명망도 있고
자녀는 모두 셋이에요
Pillars of the community, three children.
하나가 없네요
Minus one.
아들이 하나 있어요, 제시요
Uh, a son... Jesse.
작년에 실종됐고
RV차량에 타고 있는 게
Disappeared last year. Last confirmed
sighting had him boarding an RV
47번 도로 휴게소에서 목격됐어요
at a rest stop on Route 47.
- 가출이나 유괴.. 둘 중의 하나겠죠
- 둘 다이거나요
- Possible runaway, probable abduction.
- Or both.
불행은 역시 혼자 오지 않네요
When misery rains, it pours.
모두 가면을 쓰고 있어요
False faces in family portraits.
겹겹이 가려진 거짓말들이
한 아이의 슬픈 눈빛에 고스란히 담겨 있어요
Layers and layers of lies,
betrayed by
a sad glint in the child's eyes.
노먼 록웰의 그림 같은데요?
Norman Rockwell with a bullet.
강제침입 흔적은?
Alright, any signs of forced entry?
- 창문도 모두 멀쩡하고 침입 흔적은 없어요
- 그럼 초인종을 눌렀군
No broken windows or torn screens.
- All sealed up tight.
- Yeah they probably rang the front door.
- 총알은 벽 위쪽과 여기에 박혔어요
- 그렇군, 총알을 빼내서 의뢰해
I got bulletholes on the upper section
of the wall,
and again over here.
Pull the slugs for ballistics.
빼내는 덴 문제없을 거예요
They aren't frangible,
shouldn't be a problem
총알이 나간 각도와
사체의 탄흔이 일치해요
Elevated termination points match
for the scene with these bodies.
두개골 탄흔의 각도나
피가 원뿔로 퍼진 거롤 봐서
Angular cranial impact coupled with
acute exit wounds,
conical spray.
밑에서 위로 쐈어요
Shooter went low to high,
probably crouching.
제시가 실종된 지 얼마나 됐죠?
When was Jesse abducted?
1년 좀 넘었어요
Uh, a little over a year ago.
그 일은 쉽게 감출 수 있어요
I can hide what happened to me.
스카프만 있으면 되거든요
All I need is a scarf to pass.
감출수록 치료는 어려워져
Hiding what happened to you
defeats the purpose of being here.
평범한 생활로 빨리 돌아가야지
Sharing will help normalize.
어차피 이제 평범하긴 틀렸어요
I'm not normal... not anymore.
너한테 일어난 일이 평범한 일은 아니지
What happened to you was a...
입을 안 여는 애들도 있어요
Some of these women
aren't even sharing.
그러면서 자기한테 일어난 일을
알아달라는게 우습죠
They speak in "little girl voices"
telling everyone what was done to them
without saying a word about it.
목소리를 가둬버리는 트라우마도 있어
Certain traumas can
arrest vocal development.
어떤 방법으로든 고통은 드러나게 되지
And victims can sometimes broadcast
victimhood involuntarily.
난 아니에요
Not me.
그럴 필요가 없으니까
That's not necessarily true.
네 상황은 이미 많은 사람이 알잖니
Your victimhood has a high profile.
스타가 되긴 했죠
Celebrity victim.
피묻은 옷을 갖고 있냐고
물어보는 사람도 있어요
Someone here asked me
if I kept my stained clothes.
그래서 기분이 어땠어?
How did that make you feel?
집에 가고 싶었어요
Like I wanted to go home.
이젠 돌아갈 집도 없지만요
But I don't have a home anymore, do I?
다시 갖게 될거야
내가 도와줄게
You will. You will,
I'll help you find it.
집단 치료를 한번 믿어봐
Abigail I'd like you to give
the support group another chance.
그 사람들만 보면 말라죽을 것 같아요
Supportgroups are
sucking the life out of me.
고립되는 건 너한테 좋을 거 없어
Well isolation can suck just as much.
경험을 나눌 수 있는 공동체를 가져야 해
You have to find someone to relate to
in this experience.
안녕하세요?
Hi.
- 약속을 했었나?
- 맥주 있어요?
- Do you have an appointment?
- Do you have a beer?
애비게일 치료는 잘 돼가?
Interesting day with Abigail?
슬픔 표출 치료와 트라우마 중재
Yeah, with grief work.
Trauma, intervention.
전부 진행하고 있어요
It's all on course.
우울증 증세가 보이는 것 같아요
I think she might be wrestling
with a low grade depression.
그래?
She?
이 정돈 비밀유지 규정에 어긋나지 않겠죠?
Nothing wrong with a little
self medication, right Doctor?
의사로서 선을 지키기가 힘드네요
Professional neutrality be damned.
한 걸음 떨어져서 지켜봐야 하잖아요
It's so hard to watch
a bright young girl go so adrift.
치료시설에서 내보낼 때가 되지 않았나?
Perhaps it's time Abigail is released
from clinical treatment.
어디로요?
다시 야생으로요?
Released where?
Back into the wild?
비극 속에 갇혀 사는 게
더해가 될 수 도 있어
Spending each day immersed in tragedy
may be doing more harm than good.
세상에 나가야 해
She should be out in the world.
현실에 발을 디뎌야
앞으로 나갈 자신감을 얻지
Finding her footing, giving her
the confidence to move forward.
- 아직 세상의 시선과 싸울 준비가..
- 애비게일을 포기하라는 게 아냐
Abigail is in no condition
to tackle her real world issues.
- Where's she gonna live?
- I'm not suggesting abandonment.
부모와의 유착이 강했던 아이예요
Hannibal this is a girl who was
very attached to her parents.
섣부른 아빠 노릇은
의존심만 심어줄 거예요
You stepping in as a surrogate,
would only be a crutch.
안전한 울타리 안에서
스스로 서는 법을 배워야
I think Abigail need to figure
things out for herself in a safe
clinical environment.
앞으로 나갈 자신감도 생길 거예요
And that will give her
the confidence to move forward.
박사의 열정은 언제나 존경스럽군
I defer to the passion
of my esteemed colleague.
열정은 좋은 거지
Passion's good.
혈관을 뜨겁게 하거든
Gets blood pumping.
아마 우리 집에 총이 있었으면
I'm glad we didn't have guns in my house.
욕실을 차지한 누이들을 다 쏴버렸을 거야
Would have shot my sisters
just to get them out of the bathroom.
난 대가족인 게 좋았어요
I liked having a big family.
난 쌍둥이야
내가 둘이라 근사하지?
My parents gave me a gift,
a twin.
Who wouldn't want two of me?
윌은 외아들이죠?
Let me guess... only child.
왜 그렇게 생각해요?
Why do you say that?
형제간의 갈등은
성격발달에 중요하거든요
Because family friction is usually
a catalyst for personality development.
난 첫째라서 늘 대접받고 컸어요
I was the oldest so...
all the friction rolled downhill.
맞아, 관심과 책임은 첫 아이 차지지
Yes, all the intention and responsibility
is heaved on firstborn children.
그래서 첫째가 가장 성공하는 거고
Prepares them for
success in the future.
내 동생은 뭐든 맘대로였어요
My babysister got away with murder.
제대로 하는 게 없었죠
She had them all fooled.
우리도 둘째가 그랬어
I thought middles where the problem.
제일 편하잖아
Middle's the sweet spot.
어디에 붙을지 늘 머리를 써야 하죠
Always trying to figure out
where they fit in.
잘 풀리면 위대한 정치인이 되고
They can be great... politicians.
안 풀리면 골칫덩이예요
Or lousy ones.
터너 부인만 방어한 흔적이 없어요
All the victims have defensive wounds
except for Mrs. Turner.
용서한 거죠
There's forgiveness.
죽음의 순가에 살인자를
용서할 사람이 있을까요?
What kind of victim forgives their killer
at the moment of death?
엄마요
A mother.
- 어머니 얘기를 해봐요
- 너무 편한 길을 택하네요
- Tell me about your mother.
- Some lazy psychiatry Doctor Lecter.
쉽게 딸 수 있는 과일이에요
Low hanging fruit.
- 맛있는 과일은 너무 높아 따기가 어렵죠
- 어머니가 그랬어요
I suspect that fruit is on a high branch.
- Very difficult to reach.
- So is my mother.
- 알 수 없는 분이셨죠
- 거기부터 시작해 볼까요?
- Never knew her.
- An interesting place to start.
박사 어머니는요?
거기부터 시작하죠
Tell me about your mother,
let's start there.
부모님 모두 어릴 때 돌아가셨어요
Both my parents died
when I was very young.
고아원에서 지내다
16살에 삼촌한테 입양됐죠
The proverbial orphan until I was adopted
by my Uncle Robertos when I was 16.
고아라는 건 애비게일과 같에요
You have orphan in common
with Abigail Hobbs.
윌, 나 애비게일은
공통점이 아주 많아요
I think you'll discover that you and I have
a great deal in common with Abigail.
애비게일은 벌써 심리학에
소질을 보이거든요
She's already demonstrated an aptitude
for the psychological.
'가족'이라는 말은 내게 너무 낯설어요
There's something so foreign about family,
몸에 안 맞는 옷이랄까
like an ill fitting suit.
아무튼 나랑은 안 어울려요
I never connected to the concept.
하지만 가족을 만들었잖아요
You created a family for yourself.
맞아요, 유기견들이 이젠 내 가족이죠
I've only connected a family of strays,
밥 챙겨준 거 고마웠어요
and thank you for feeding them
while I was away.
난 애비게일을 말한 거예요
I was referring to Abigail.
터너 가족은 어땠어요?
부유했나요?
Tell me about the Turner family,
were they affluent, well to do?
부족한 것 없이 살았어요
They lived like they had money.
- 윌 가족은요?
- 우린 가난했어요
- Did your family have money Will?
- We were poor.
아버지가 배를 수리하셨기 때문에
I followed my father
from the boatyards of
빌록시, 그린빌, 이리까지
일을 따라 옮겨 다녔죠
Biloxi and Greenville,
to lakeboats on Eerie.
학교에서 늘 이방인이었겠군요
Always the new boy at school,
always the stranger.
맞아요
Always.
살인범은 왜 터너 부인을
죽이고 싶었을까요?
What grudge was Mrs. Turner's killer
harboring against her.
모성이 그리웠겠죠
Motherhood.
변질된 모성 때문은 아니었을까요?
Not motherhood.
A perversion of it.
요리책에 있는 블랙 푸딩을
변형해 봤어요
A modified Boudin Noir
from Ali Bab's Gastronomie Practique.
부인이 함께 오셨으면
좋았을 텐데요
You promised to deliver
your wife to my dinner table.
우리 부부문제까지
분석하는 건 사양하겠어요
Well we'll have to polish up our act,
we can't have
you diagnosing our marital problems
all in one fell swoop.
- 이건 무슨 고기죠?
- 토끼요
- What am I about to put in my mouth?
- Rabbit.
- 걸음이 느린 토끼였나 보네요
- 네, 맞아요
- He should have hopped faster.
- Yes he should have.
더 빨리 뛰었으면 살 수도 있었죠
- But fortunately for us he did not.
- Mmm mmm.
윌이 넔이 나간 것 같더군요
Our friend Will seems haunted today.
윌의 베개 밑에 숨어 있는
악몽 때문이겠죠
We don't know what nightmares
lie coiled beneath Will's pillow.
아이가 아이를 죽이는 그림이
편치 않은 것 같아요
Children killing other children is...
not that unfamiliar a notion to Will.
아직도 애비게일이
공범이라고 생각하세요?
He still suspects Abigail Hobbs
in her father's crimes.
그걸 인정하게 돼서
더 괴로운 게 아닐까요?
Perhaps the nightmare under Will's pillow,
is that he was wrong about her.
아이들은 어린 시절을
떠올리는 매개가 되죠
Children transport us to our childhoods.
윌은 현재의 삶이
흔들리는 배라고 느껴요
Will may feel the tug of life
before the FBI, before you.
아버지와 함께했을 때는
Simpler times in boatyards with dad.
풍랑에 떠내려가지 않게
윌을 묶어주는 닻이 있었죠
That life is an anchor streamed behind him
in heavy weather.
윌에겐 닻이 필요합니다
He needs an anchor Jack.
터너 집에서 나온 235mm 운동화예요
One pair of size 6 sneakers
from the Turner house.
왼쪽만 닳은 걸 보니 다리 길이가 달라요
The thread on left
indicates uneven leg length.
- 그게 이상한가?
- 12살짜리 성장판은 불안정하다고
- Is that unusual?
- Mmm, not in a 12 year old.
Growth plates all out of whack.
한쪽이 컸다 길었다 하다가
사춘기에 제대로 자릴 잡지
Got one foot that's bigger,
one leg that's longer,
puberty in full effect.
실종된 지 1년이면 얼마나 컸을까요?
How did Jesse Turner turn out?
No one has seen him in over a year.
유괴 아동 자료로 추측해볼 수 있어
I extrapolated the present
height and weight
from abduction stats.
12살 평균치로 보면
키는 137cm 몸무게는 36kg 정도지
Even with the usual growth spurts
between eleven and twelve
he'd be four and a half feet,
eighty pounds tops.
오늘 횡재수가 있었네
God's gift to trace analysts.
기름 묻은 손으로 만진 지문이야
Greasy fingerprints all over these things.
뭔가 나오겠는데?
No matches but they're gorgeous.
현장에 있던 발자국 중
터너 가족 걸 빼면
Isolated seven pairs of shoe prints.
Filtered out the Turner's
including Jessie's,
세 개가 미상으로 남아요
운동화 사이즈는 245, 210, 285예요
so we're down to three unsubs,
sneakers are sizes seven
three and a half, and a boy's eleven.
'사라진 소년들'이네
The lost boy.
하나는 찾은 것 같은데?
I think I found one of them.
성폭행 후 남은 이빨 자국은
중앙이 검은 게 일반적으로
Most of the time in sexual assaults,
the bite mark has a livid spot
이는 성복행 시 생긴 멍입니다
at the center, a "suck bruise."
물론 예외도 있어요
In some cases it does not.
- 어떤 살인자들이 경우엔 무는 행위가...
- 강의는 여기까지! 모두 나가요
For some killers biting may be
a fighting pattern
- As much as a sexual behaviour.
- Ok, class dismissed. Everyone out!
내 말 안 들려? 어서 나가!
What did I just say?! Let's go!
이젠 강의실까지 쳐들어오는 겁니까?
You're making it difficult
to provide an education Jack.
살해현장에서 나온 지문이
13살짜리 실종 아동과 일치해요
We found a match to a set of prints
we pulled from the Turner home
they belong to a thirteen year old boy
from Reston, Virginia.
이름은 코너 프리스트
His name is Connor Frist.
- 다른 아이는요?
- 역시 실종 아동이에요
- Another kid?
- Another missing kid.
열 달 전에 사라져서 오리무중이었어요
Vanished ten months ago,
case was never solved.
- 프리스트 부부한텐 자녀가 몇 명이죠?
- 터너 부부처럼 셋이에요
- How many kids in the Frist family?
- Three, just like the Turner family.
준비됐으면 출발합시다
We're ready to go when you are,
and you're ready to go now so, let's go.
죽었을 거라고 생각하는군요
You're expecting a crime scene.
프리스트 씨와 아이들을 먼저 죽이고
부인이 마지막이었어
Mr. Frist and the children killed first
saving Mrs. Frist for last.
- 터너 가족과 같아
- 완벽히 같진 않아요
- Same as the Turners.
- Not exactly the same.
뭔가 문제가 있었어요
Something went wrong.
프리스트 부인 선물은 하나도 없었어요
Not a single present under the tree
for Mrs. Frist.
모성애 대신해 선물을 가져갔군요
He took her presents,
he took her motherhood.
한 발로 끝나지 않았어요
Shooting her once wasn't enough.
첫 번째가 두개골 아래에서
목 뒤로 나갔거든요
The first bullet, travels beneath her scalp
to it's final resting place,
base of her neck.
죽진 않았겠군
And it still didn't kill her.
두개골에 가해진 충격으로
뇌 손상은 있었을 거예요
Hydrostatic shock of shell hitting skull
would have caused brain damage.
- 몸이 경련을 일으켰어요
- 두 번째로 숨을 끊었어요 다른 총으로요
- Her body went into convulsions.
- He shot her again.
Put her out of her misery,
different gun.
다른 누군가가 코너 엄마를 쏜 거죠
So, someone else shot Connor's mom.
그럼 벽난로에 있던 사체는?
So who is our additional corpse
in the fireplace?
코너 프리스트예요
I'd say Connor Frist.
엄마가 고통스러워하자
코너는 당황했어요
He'd been prepped to shot his mother,
not watch her suffer.
코너가 문제를 일으켜서
처리해버린 거군
Connor couldn't put his panic
back in the bottle.
So he got shot too.
죽임으로써
가족의 끈을 끊은 거죠
Whoever shot him
disowned him.
코너 일은 너무 슬퍼하지 마요
Don't be sad about Connor.
코너가 제대로 이해를 못 한 모양이야
I guess I couldn't make him understand.
너희가 태어난 가족은 진짜 가족이 아냐
The family you're born into
isn't really family.
너희가 선택하지 않았잖아
우리가 진짜 가족이야
Cause they're just people you didn't choose
you have to make family, that's what we're
doing, we're making our family.
엄마 가족은 어떻게 됐어요?
What happened to your family.
엄마 가족은 우리야
We're her family.
다른 가족 말이에요
I meant... your other family.
예날 가족은 진짜 가족에게
가기 위한 과정에 불과해
The family you think is family, is just
a steppingstone to real family.
괜찮니, 아가?
Are you feeling ok sweetie pie?
당연히 괜찮죠
He's fine.
집에 가니까 좋지?
You should be excited to go home.
하지만 작별하러 가는거야
네 가족은 이제 우리니까
Even if it is to say goodbye,
`cause we're your family now Christopher.
가족이 두 개일 순 없어
You can only have one family.
윌러드 위건 알아요?
Ever heard of Willard Wigan?
초정밀 조각을 하는 아티스트예요
He's this artist that does micro sculptures.
오바마 대통령 일가에
바늘구멍을 넣었죠
Like, putting the Obamas
in the eye of a needle.
심장박동이 손을 흔들까 봐
숨도 조절한대요
He's so focused that he can work
between beats of his heart.
양궁선수들도 그렇겠죠?
I guess archers do the same thing right?
Hmm?
뭘 보는 거예요?
What are you looking at?
두 아이 모두 또래에 비해 작아요
Both these kids are small,
underweight for their age.
사건과 관계가 있을까요?
You think there's a connection?
두 아이 모두 ADHA일 수 있어요
I'm thinking possible ADHD diagnosis
for both boys.
메틸페니데이트 성분의 약은
식욕저하를 일으켜 성장을 방해하죠
Ritalin, Focalin, any medication
containing Methylphenidate
can affect appetite
and slow long term growth in kids.
윌러드 위건도 외로운
유년시절을 보냈대요
Another thing about Willard Wigan
he had a lonely childhood.
조각이 탈출구였던 셈이죠
He used his tiny sculptures as an escape.
윌러드 위건이 누군데요?
Who's Willard Wigan?
일치하는 탄흔이 있는 지
프로그램을 돌려 봤는데
Price got a hit on the
ballistics matching program
he's been running
on the two family murders.
프리스트 부인을 죽인 총알이
1년 전 뱅고어 사건과 같아요
The bullet that put Mrs. Frist
out of her misery matches
three used in a murder
in Bangor, Maine a year ago.
13살 남자아이 엄마가
자기 총에 맞은 사건이요
Mother of a thirteen year old boy
shot to death with her own gun.
13살짜리 실종된 남자아이요?
Thirteen year old milk carton material.
CJ 링컨은 엄마가 살해되기
여섯 달 전에 실종 됐어요
C.J Lincoln disappeared six months
before his mother's murder.
He hasn't been seen since.
반사회적 행동은 보인 적이 없군요
He has none of the characteristics
of a sadist or a sociopath
절도, 기물파손, 공갈 폭행도 없었고
동물을 사랑하는 아이였어요
Right, no shoplifting, no
malicious destruction of property.
No assault, no battery,
he was kind to animals for Gods sake.
사라진 소년들의 피터팬이네요
Firearm says we are looking at
Peter Pan to our lost boys.
방아쇠를 당기게 할 정도로
아이들을 조종할 수 있었을까요?
But it takes a sophisticated level
of manipulation to convince
young boys to kill
their families in cold blood.
상당한 심리조작 기술이 필요했겠죠
Kindness to animals doesn't suggest that
particular kind of sophistication.
나이도 많고 거리생활도 오래 했으니까
Well, he's older, he's
been out in the world.
절도 기록이 있을지도 모르겠군요
Maybe he picked up a few things.
여기요
There you go.
고마워요
Thank you so much.
세상에! 이걸 어째...
Oh honey... Oh geez...
괜찮니, 아가?
Are you feeling ok honey?
열이 있나?
You have a fever?
- 뜨겁진 않은데
- 여기요
- You don't feel warm.
- Here you go ma'am.
고마워요
이런 적이 없었는데
Oh thank you. He hasn't done this before.
- 휴지 값은 낼게요
- 안 그려셔도 돼요
- I'll pay for the napkins.
- Don't worry about it.
이런, 아가
Oh honey, oh gee whiz...
엄마 창피하게...
I'm so embarrassed.
넌 창피할 거 없어
너도 모르게 그런 거니까
But you shouldn't feel embarrassed,
this happens with little bladders, right?
그렇지?
Right?
어서와요, 윌
들어와요
Good evening Will, please come in.
이른 크리스마스 선물인가요?
아니면 늦은 선물?
Has christmas come early?
Or late?
- 애비게일한테 주고 싶었어요
- 그런데요?
- Was for Abigail.
- Was?
너무 화가 난 상태여서
판단을 잘못한 거 같아요
I thought better of it, I wasn't thinking
straight, I was upset when I bought it.
아직도 화가 풀리지 않아요
Maybe still am.
- 뭔데요?
- 돋보기요
- What is it?
- A magnifying glass.
플라잉 낚시 도구죠
Fly tying gear.
낚시를 가르치려고요?
Teaching her how to fish,
- 아빠한테 사냥을 배웠죠
- 그래서 그만두기로 했어요
- her father taught her how to hunt.
- That's why I thought better of it.
- 부모 같은 책임감을 느껴요?
- 박사는요?
- Pretty paternal Will.
- Aren't you?
나도 그래요
Yes.
블룸 박사는 애비게일에게
지나친 관심을 갖지 말라더군요
Our good friend Doctor Bloom
has advised against taking
to personal an interest
in Abigail's welfare.
왜 화가 났어요?
Tell me why are you so angry?
그 아이들을 찾는다 해도
도와줄 수 없는 게 화가 나요!
I'm angry about those boys, I'm angry cause
I know when I find them, I can't help them.
아이들이 버린 걸 돌려 줄 수 없어요
I can't, I can't give them back
what they just gave away.
가족이요?
Family.
그래요
Yeah.
길을 잃어버린 아이들이에요
We call them "The lost boys."
애비게일도 길을 잃었어요
Abigail's lost too.
그 애에게 길을 찾아주는 게
우리 의무죠
And perhaps it's our responsibility
yours and mine to help her find her way.
담 넘은 것 때문에
외출금지인 줄 알았어요
I don't think I'm allowed to leave,
after I climb the fence.
내가 잘 얘기했어
I've made arrangements.
난 네 보호자니까
You could say I'm, one of your guardians.
- 어디 갈 건데요?
- 집에 갈거야 우리 집
- Where are we going?
- Home, my home.
내 요리가 맘에 들 거야
I thought you might enjoy
if I cooked for you.
- 취침시간 전에 데려다 줄게
- 거기서 자면 안 돼요?
- I'll have you back before bedtime.
- Can't I spend the night?
여기서 자기 싫어요
악몽을 꾸거든요
I don't like sleeping here,
I have bad dreams.
- 잠은 네 침대에서 자야지
- 이건 내 침대가 아니에요
- You have to sleep in your own bed.
- This isn't my bed.
어떤 악몽인지 얘기해줄래?
Tell me about your bad dreams.
전에 꿨던 꿈에선
마리사가 사진을 보냈어요
I had one where
Marissa was sending me picture texts.
니콜라스 보일이 죽어 있는 사진이요
Like crime scene photos of Nicholas Boyle.
- 배가 갈린 채로요
- 네 손으로 가른 거야
- Gutted.
- How you left him.
사람들이 절 아빠 같은
살인마로 볼까 봐 무서워요
Even though she's dead
I'm afraid that Marissa's gonna
tell everyone I killed him
and they'll think I'm just like my dad.
죄송해요
Sorry.
이런 얘긴 집단 치료 때 할 수가 없거든요
Can't really talk about this in group.
비밀은 지켜져야 해
You don't have that luxury Abigail.
그런데 거짓말이 익숙해지질 않아요
I just have to get used to lying.
딱 하나에 대해서만 거짓말하면 돼
You only have to lie about one thing.
나하고 있을 땐 하지 않아도 되고
And when you're with me
you don't have to lie about anything.
꿈을 꾸고 있을 땐... 그런 짓을 하고도
살 수 있을까 생각해요
In the dream I wonder
how I could live with myself.
Knowing what I did.
깨어났을 땐?
And when you're awake?
살 수 있다는 걸 알게 되죠
When I'm awake I know I can
live with myself.
결국 익숙해질 거라는 걸요
And I'll just get used to what I did.
- 제가 미쳐가는 건가요?
- 아니
- Does that make me a sociopath?
- No.
생존법을 배우고 있는 거야
It makes you a survivor.
새로 시작할 때를 아는 건 중요해
It's important to know
when it's time to turn the page.
대학을 지원하는 건 생각해봤니?
Have you thought about
applying for schools?
지원했던 대학 모두
아빠 피해자들이 다닌 학교예요
My dad killed girls
from all the schools I applied to.
- 그럼 좀 더 기다려야겠구나
- FBI에서 일하고 싶어요
- Perhaps that can wait then.
- I wanna work for the FBI.
네가 FBI에서 일한다면
내가 더 안전해지겠구나
I would certainly feel safer
if you were in the FBI,
protecting my interests.
일하게 해주지 않겠죠?
They wouldn't let me though,
would they?
아빠가 살인마니까요
Because of what my dad did.
너한테도 그 피가 흐른다고 생각하니?
Only if they believe
that's in your nature too.
후천적인 학습도 했잖아요
Nature versus nurture.
넌 이제 네 아빠 딸이 아냐
You're not your father's daughter,
not anymore.
그 일을 생각할 때마다 느끼는 고통이
사라진다면 어떨까?
What if it weren't so painful anymore,
to think of him.
- 아빠 일이요?
- 그래
- My dad?
- Yes.
'실로시빈' 알아?
Have you ever tried Psilocybin?
- 버섯에 든 거요? 끓이는 게 그거예요?
- 그래
- Mushrooms? That's what's in the tea?
- Yes.
트라우마 기억에 접근하는 걸
도와준다고 알려져 있어
There are those psychiatrists who believe
altered states could be used
to access traumatic memories.
그 기억엔 언제든 접근할 수 있어요
원하는 만큼요
I have all the access to
traumatic memories I need.
Unlimited access.
그래서 긍정적인 연상을
도와줄 게 필요한 거야
Which is why we need to supplement them
with positive associations.
이제 악몽을 꾸지 않아도 돼
No more bad dreams Abigail.
- 환각제를 마시란 말이예요?
- 내 감독하에서 마시면 도움이 될 거야 안전하니까
- You want me to do drugs?
- I want you to do this drug.
With my supervision it's quite safe.
날 믿지?
Do you trust me?
메인 주, 뱅고어
Bangor, Maine.
코네티컷 주, 스탬포드
Stanford, Connecticut.
가장 최근은 버지니아 주, 레스톤이야
And recently Reston, Virginia.
- 범행 장소 간의 거리가 800km는 넘어요
- 맞아
This places each of the murders
approximately five hundred miles
- from the one before it.
- Right.
시기도 몇 주씩 떨어져 있는데
지역적으로 연결이 가능할까요?
You 're trying to establish a geographical
pattern, when the murders were weeks apart.
공통점이 있어요
침입자들이 모두 어리고 유복한 가정의 둘째죠
Other patterns too our shooters are minors
middle children from
traditional affluent families.
이동 방향이 남쪽이니까 노스캐롤라이나 경계를 지켜
We know they're moving South, so that means
we wanna cover the border of North Carolina
and Georgia.
- 경계를 기점으로 300km 근방에
아이들 실종 전단도 뿌려 - 공통점이 또 있어요
We need to get files
on every missing boy within
- two hundred miles of North Carolina.
- There's a pattern,
지역적이 아닌 심리적인 공통점이죠
less to do with geography
than psychology.
범행을 저지르는 심리요?
What kind of kid does this?
범행을 저지르는 아이를 따르는 심리요
And what kind of kid follows
a kid who does this?
폭력적인 가정에서 자란 아이들이 아니에요
There's no indication that these kids
came from abusive families.
아뇨, 아뇨
No, no, no.
'포로 유대'
Capture bonding.
새 주인에 대한 심리반응으로
인간의 오랜 생존기술이죠
A passive psychological
response to a new master
has been an essential survival tool
for a million years.
포획자와 유대를 형성해 살아남는 겁니다
Bond with your captor,
you survive.
그렇지 않으면 먹히니까요
You don't...
you're breakfast.
가르쳐준 대로만 해
Just like we talked about.
선생님한텐 허락받았어요?
Doctor Bloom said this was ok.
아니
우린 종종 의견 차이가 있지
Not at all, we often
have a difference of opinion.
비밀이 더 생겼네요
- More secrets for us.
- Well.
너와 난 많은 비밀을 갖게 될 거야
You and I will have many secrets.
심리치료 전에
실로시빈이 혈관에 들어가면
Infusing Psilosybin into the bloodstream
before psychotherapy
환자에게 긍정적이고
영적인 경험을 줄 수 있어
can illicit a positive even spiritual
experience for patients.
심리적 트라우마는
힘을 잃은 데서 오는 고통이지
Psychological trauma is an affliction
of the powerless.
난 네게 힘을 돌려주고 싶어
I want to give you your power back.
기분이 안 좋아요
I don't feel so good.
그 기분은 곧 지나가
That feeling will pass.
널 말끔히 씻어내도록 내버려 둬
Allow it to wash over you, through you.
내 말만 따르면 돼
Let me be your guide.
아침 메뉴가 저녁이네요?
You're making breakfast for dinner?
'하이라이프 에그'
High *** for eggs.
스페인 셰프 뮤로가
19세기에 발명한 요리지
A chef in Spain called Muro claimed
he invented it in the 19th century.
맛을 느끼는 덴
심리적 요인이 커
Taste, is not only biochemical...
it's also psychological.
부모님과 마지막으로 먹은 게
소시지와 달걀이에요
Sausage and eggs was the last meal
I was having with my parents.
알아, 나하고 먹는
첫 식사이기도 하지
I know. It's also the first meal
you're having with me.
누구의 지시가 아니고선
폭력성을 보일 아이들이 아니에요
Without the interference of a leader
these kids would never
consider violent action.
모두 남자아이예요
Our missing kid is a boy.
평범한 가정의 둘째이면서
어디에도 못 섞이는 아웃사이더죠
A paradox in the midst of a normal family
he's an outsider who doesn't look like one.
발명이나 기계 쪽으로 특기가 있을 거예요
He'd have a vocation.
Something inventive or mechanical.
여기 있네요
Here's one.
가족이 3년 동안
빌록시, 찰스톤, 페이엇빌로 이사
Family moved from Biloxi to Charleston
to Fayettville in the last three years.
컴퓨터로 회로를 만들어서
중학교 때 과학상을 탔어요
He won a junior high award
for his work on
pretty sophisticated computer circuitry.
아이들이 CJ 링컨을 따르는 이유는요?
Why do you think these kids
are susceptible to C.J Lincoln?
형이 있었지만 유대에 문제가 있었다면
CJ를 형과 동일시할 수 있어요
Cause our boy may have a brother
but their ages or their interests
keep them apart, so he's a brother
without a brother.
그 공식을 엄마에게 적용하면요?
Brothers looking for a mother.
모두 엄마를 마지막에 죽였잖아요
They're killing the mothers last.
네?
Yeah.
CJ 링컨이 아니에요
It's not just C.J Lincoln.
엄마 행세를 하는 조종자가 따로 있어요
There's an adult with some
formative sway. It's a woman
a mother figure I think.
가족을 만들고 싶어하고요
And she's looking to form a family.
'가족'이 때론 전염성을 갖기도 하죠
A family can have a
contagion effect on some people.
선망하는 가족의 행동패턴을
흉내 내는 경우처럼요
Influences them to adopt
similar behaviors and attitudes.
아이들에게 확인받고 싶어했어요
Whoever this woman is,
she wants these children
자신에 대한 사랑을요
to burst with love for her.
그러기 위해선 진짜 가족을 없애야 했겠죠
But... she has to erase
their family to do that.
아이들을 납치해서
So she abducts them.
자신의 사랑을 믿게 한 다음
보답을 강요했군요
Convinces them no one
can love them as much
as she does, and then
makes damn sure of it.
알렉산드리아의 편의점 CCTV에
크리스토퍼가 잡혔는데
A security camera in...
a convenient store in Alexandria, Virginia
caught footage of one Chris O'Halloran
한 여자와 함께였어요
this morning, he was with
an unidentified woman.
- 부모님은 어디 살죠?
- 노스캐롤라이나 주 페이엇빌이요
- Where's this kids parents?
- Fayettville, North Carolina.
- 크리스토퍼?
- 안녕, 엄마
- Christopher?
- Hi mom.
세상에!
Oh my God.
크리스토퍼
Chris.
안 돼! 안 돼!
No, no, no.
Down! Down on the ground right now!
크리스토퍼, 기다려!
Chris wait.
쏘지 마요
Don't shoot.
괜찮아
It's ok.
여긴 네 집이야
어서 총 내려놔
You're home now,
put the gun down Christopher.
어서 쏴, 크리스토퍼
Shoot him Christopher.
크리스토퍼
Christopher.
제발...
Please.
집에 가도 돼요?
Can I go home now?
한참 동안은 집에 가기 힘들 거야
Well I don't think you're gonna
go home for a long time.
네가 가족을 죽이러 온 건
명백한 사실이니까
You came here to kill your family,
that's all anybody knows.
지금은 다른 방법이 없어
It may be all that anyone ever believes.
전 그럴 생각 없었어요
I wasn't gonna do it.
많은 사람들에게 그 얘길 해야 할 거야
Well you're gonna have to talk
to a lot of people about it.
네가 하려던 일이 뭔지도
이해시켜야 할 거고
And those people are gonna try
and help you understand
what you were really trying to do.
여기 가족은...
She told me
진짜 가족이 아니랬어요
that they weren't my family,
그래서 가족을 만들어야 한댔죠
that we had to make our own family.
아저씨도 가족이 있어요?
Do you have a family?
난 아니들이 없어
I don't have any children, no.
그럼 아저씬 모르겠네요
Then you don't know what it like.
엄마랑 얘기할 수 있어요?
Can I talk to my mom?
진짜 엄마요
My real mom.
곧 그럴 수 있을 거야
In a little while.
하지만 그 전에 나와 얘기해야 해
But first I need you to talk to me.
예의를 중요하시하는 분이
좀 이해가 안 되네요
As someone who makes such a deal
about common courtesy
I'm a little taken a back.
아니, 이건 말이 안 돼요
내 환자를...
Slash a lot taken a back,
that you would take my patient
내 환자를
my patient
내 허가 없이 데리고 나왔어요
out of the hospital without my permission.
이번엔 이 정도로 해두죠
다신 이런 짓 하지 마세요
And I'm not a professional scold
but don't put me
in this position ever again.
미안해
I'm sorry.
이건 정말이지 무례한 짓이라고요!
Rude! Hannibal shockingly rude!
내가 선을 넘었으니까
입이 열 개라도 할 말 없어
You have every right to be upset with me
I overstepped my bounds.
- 어디 있어요?
- 식탁에
- Where is she?
- She's in the dining room.
그리고.. 알라나가 옳았어
And Alana... you were right.
알아듣게 말해줄래요?
Often am. You have to be more specific.
퇴원하기엔 아직 불안정하더군
그래서 진정제를 좀 줬어
She wasn't ready to leave the hospital,
she... experienced a bit of anxiety
so I gave her a sedative.
- 무슨 진정제요?
- 바륨 반 알이야 약간 어지러울 거야
- Sedative what did you give her?
- I only gave her half a Valium
but she may be a little hazy.
- 선생님 오셨어요?
- 안녕, 애비게일
- Hi Doctor Bloom.
- Hello Abigail.
내가 올 줄 알았어요?
You were expecting me?
앉지
Please.
배고프세요?
You hungry?
박사님이 저녁을 준비하셨어요
Hannibal made breakfast for dinner.
그럼 같이 먹을까?
I could eat.
왜 그래?
What is it?
애비게일?
Abigail.
뭐가 보여?
What do you see?
가족이요
I see family.
여보
Hello.
우릴 위해 아일 갖는 거 어때?
Think it's to late for us to have kids?
당신을 위해서라면 싫어
It is for me.